At Monarch, we take your privacy seriously. Please read this Privacy Policy to learn how we treat your personal data. **By using or accessing our Services in any manner, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined below, and you hereby consent that we will collect, use and share your information as described in this Privacy Policy.**

Remember that your use of Monarch's Services is at all times subject to our [Terms of Use](https://www.monarchmoney.com/terms), which incorporates this Privacy Policy. Any terms we use in this Policy without defining them have the definitions given to them in the Terms of Use.

You may print a copy of this Privacy Policy by clicking here. If you have a disability, you may access this Privacy Policy in an alternative format by contacting [\[email protected\]](https://www.monarchmoney.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Summary of our Privacy Policy**

We know, Privacy Policies are no fun. Here at Monarch, our goal is to help make managing money less complicated. In the course of providing our Services, we will collect certain information about you which is necessary for us to best achieve that goal. Our intent is to only collect the information we need to best serve you. You'll note that there may be references to "selling" and "sharing" in this Privacy Policy. Please note that those definitions are only used as they relate to certain online advertising activities related to our use of Cookies on our website (certain privacy laws define terms like "selling" and "sharing" very broadly). We will never sell your financial data.

**Privacy Policy Table of Contents**

[Our Commercial or Business Purposes for Collecting Personal Data](#commercial-purposes)

**What this Privacy Policy Covers**

This Privacy Policy covers how we treat Personal Data that we gather when you access or use our Services. “Personal Data” means any information that identifies or relates to a particular individual and also includes information referred to as “personally identifiable information” or “personal information” under applicable data privacy laws, rules or regulations. This Privacy Policy does not cover the practices of companies we don't own or control or people we don't manage.

**Categories of Personal Data We Collect**

This chart details the categories of Personal Data that we collect and have collected over the past 12 months:

| Category of Personal Data (and Examples) | Business or Commercial Purpose(s) for Collection | Categories of Third Parties With Whom We Share this Personal Data: |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Profile or Contact Data such as first and last name, email, and login information** | * Providing, Customizing and Improving the Services<br>* Marketing the Services<br>* Corresponding with You | * Service Providers<br>* Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate |
| **Payment Data** such as payment card type, last 4 digits of your payment card, expiration date, billing address, phone number, and email | * Providing, Customizing and Improving the Services<br>* Corresponding with You | * Service Providers (specifically our payment processing partners, currently Stripe, Inc. ("Stripe"), the Apple Inc. App Store ("Apple"), or the Google Inc. Play Store ("Google") |
| **Commercial and Debt-Related Data such as financial transactions, balances of financial accounts, credit reports, credit score, and other information about outstanding debt** | * Providing, Customizing and Improving the Services<br>* Corresponding with You | * Service Providers<br>* Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate |
| **Device/IP Data such as IP address, device ID, domain server, and type of device/ operating system/ browser used to access the Services.** | * Providing, Customizing and Improving the Services<br>* Marketing the Services<br>* Corresponding with You | * Service Providers<br>* Advertising Partners |
| **Web Analytics such as web page interactions, referring webpage/source through which you accessed the Services, non-identifiable request IDs, and statistics associated with the interaction between device or browser and the Services.** | * Providing, Customizing and Improving the Services<br>* Marketing the Services<br>* Corresponding with You | * Service Providers<br>* Advertising Partners |
| **Consumer Demographic Data such as age/date of birth and zip code** | * Providing, Customizing and Improving the Services<br>* Corresponding with You | * Service Providers<br>* Advertising Partners |
| **Sensory Data such as photos, videos or recordings, such as a profile photo or a recorded interview (collected with your consent)** | * Providing, Customizing and Improving the Services<br>* Marketing the Services | * Service Partners<br>* Analytics Partners<br>* Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate |
| **Categories of Data Considered “Sensitive” Under the CCPA** such as<br><br>* Health Data to the extent it relates to an outstanding debt<br>* Personal identification numbers, including social security, driver’s license, passport, or state ID card numbers; | * Providing, Customizing and Improving the Services<br>* Corresponding with you<br>We do not collect Sensitive Data for the purpose of inferring characteristics about you. | * Service Providers<br>* Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate |
| **Inferences Drawn From Other Personal Data Collected specifically, in relating to your use of our Services** | * Providing, Customizing and Improving the Services | * Service Providers<br>* Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate |
| **Other Identifying Information that You Voluntarily Choose to Provide such as emails, letters, texts, or other communications you send us.** | * Providing, Customizing and Improving the Services<br>* Corresponding with You | * Service Providers<br>* Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate |

_Categories of Sources of Personal Data_

We collect Personal Data about you from the following categories of sources:

* **You**
    * When you provide such information directly to us.
        * When you create an account or use our interactive tools and Services.
        * When you voluntarily provide information in free-form text boxes through the Services or through responses to surveys or questionnaires.
        * When you send us an email or otherwise contact us.
    * When you use the Services and such information is collected automatically.
        * Through Cookies (defined in the [“Tracking Tools and Opt-Out” section](#tracking-tools-and-opt-out) below).
        * If you download our mobile application or use a location-enabled browser, we may receive information about your location and mobile device, as applicable.
        * If you download and install certain applications and software we make available, we may receive and collect information transmitted from your computing device for the purpose of providing you the relevant Services, such as information regarding when you are logged on and available to receive updates or alert notices.
        * We may collect information on your use of our Site and Services, such as pages visited, links clicked, non-sensitive text entered, and mouse movements, as well as information more commonly collected such as the referring URL, browser, operating system, and IP address. We generally collect this information through our vendor, Microsoft Clarity. You can find Microsoft Clarity's privacy policy [here](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement).
    * When you connect your financial accounts to our Services
        * When you login to your financial accounts in order to connect them to our Services, we will receive transaction and balance information from such accounts via Plaid or Finicity. You can find Plaid's privacy policy [here](https://plaid.com/legal/ios/), and Finicity's privacy policy [here](https://www.finicity.com/privacy/), Mx's privacy policy [here](https://www.mx.com/privacy/), and Spinwheel's privacy policy here. At no point will we receive your login information to any of your financial accounts.
* **Third Parties**
    * Vendors
        * We may use analytics providers to analyze how you interact and engage with the Services, or third parties may help us provide you with customer support.
        * We use vendors, such as OpenAI, to power portions of the Services, including AI Services as described further in our Terms of Use.
    * Advertising Partners
        * We receive information about you from some of our vendors who assist us with marketing or promotional services related to how you interact with our websites, applications, products, Services, advertisements or communications.
    * Third-Party Credentials
        * If you provide your third-party account credentials or otherwise log into a third-party service in connection with our Services, some content and/or information in those accounts may be transmitted into your account with us.

_Our Commercial or Business Purposes for Collecting Personal Data_

* **Providing, Customizing and Improving the Services**
    * Creating and managing your account or other user profiles.
    * Processing orders or other transactions; billing.
    * Providing you with the products, services or information you request.
    * Meeting or fulfilling the reason you provided the information to us.
    * Providing support and assistance for the Services.
    * Improving the Services, including testing, research, internal analytics and product development.
    * Personalizing the Services, website content and communications based on your preferences.
    * Doing fraud protection, security and debugging.
    * Carrying out other business purposes stated when collecting your Personal Data or as otherwise set forth in applicable data privacy laws, such as the California Consumer Privacy Act (the "CCPA").
* **Marketing the Services**
    * Marketing and selling the Services.
* **Corresponding with You**
    * Responding to correspondence that we receive from you, contacting you when necessary or requested, and sending you information about Monarch or the Services.
    * Sending emails and other communications according to your preferences or that display content that we think will interest you.
* **Other Permitted Purposes for Processing Personal Data**
    
    In addition, each of the above referenced categories of Personal Data may be collected, used, and disclosed with the government, including law enforcement, or other parties to meet certain legal requirements and enforcing legal terms including:
    
    * Fulfilling our legal obligations under applicable law, regulation, court order or other legal process, such as preventing, detecting and investigating security incidents and potentially illegal or prohibited activities.
    * Protecting the rights, property or safety of you, Monarch Money or another party.
    * Enforcing any agreements with you.
    * Responding to claims that any posting or other content violates third-party rights.
    * Resolving disputes.
    
    We will not collect additional categories of Personal Data or use the Personal Data we collected for materially different, unrelated or incompatible purposes without providing you notice.
    
* **Meeting Legal Requirements and Enforcing Legal Terms**
    * Fulfilling our legal obligations under applicable law, regulation, court order or other legal process, such as preventing, detecting and investigating security incidents and potentially illegal or prohibited activities.
    * Protecting the rights, property or safety of you, Monarch or another party.
    * Enforcing any agreements with you.
    * Responding to claims that any posting or other content violates third-party rights.
    * Resolving disputes.

We will not collect additional categories of Personal Data or use the Personal Data we collected for materially different, unrelated or incompatible purposes without providing you notice.

**How We Share Your Personal Data**

We disclose your Personal Data to the categories of service providers and other parties listed in this section. Depending on state laws that may be applicable to you, some of these disclosures may constitute a "sale" of your Personal Data. For more information, please refer to the state-specific sections below.

* **Service Providers.** These parties help us provide the Services or perform business functions on our behalf. They include:
    * Hosting, technology and communication providers.
    * Security and fraud prevention consultants.
    * Support and customer service vendors.
    * Artificial Intelligence platforms (e.g., OpenAI) that power our AI Services.
    * Payment processors.
        * Our payment processing partners, Stripe, Inc. ("Stripe"), the Apple Inc. App Store ("Apple"), or the Google Inc. Play Store ("Google") collects your voluntarily-provided payment card information necessary to process your payment for our Services.
        * Please see Stripe's, Apple's, or Google's respective terms of service and privacy policy for information on its use and storage of your Personal Data.
    * **Analytics Partners.** These parties provide analytics on web traffic or usage of the Services. They include:
        * Companies that track how users found or were referred to the Services.
        * Companies that track how users interact with the Services.
    * **Business Partners.** These parties partner with us in offering various services. They include:
        * Businesses that you have a relationship with.
    * **Parties You Authorize, Access or Authenticate**
        * Third parties you access through the services.

_Legal Obligations_

We may share any Personal Data that we collect with third parties in conjunction with any of the activities set forth under "Meeting Legal Requirements and Enforcing Legal Terms" in the "Our Commercial or Business Purposes for Collecting Personal Data" section above.

_Business Transfers_

All of your Personal Data that we collect may be transferred to a third party if we undergo a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or other transaction in which that third party assumes control of our business (in whole or in part). Should one of these events occur, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you before your information becomes subject to different privacy and security policies and practices.

_Data that is Not Personal Data_

We may create aggregated, de-identified or anonymized data from the Personal Data we collect, including by removing information that makes the data personally identifiable to a particular user. We may use such aggregated, de-identified or anonymized data and share it with third parties for our lawful business purposes, including to analyze, build and improve the Services and promote our business, provided that we will not share such data in a manner that could identify you.

**Tracking Tools, Advertising, and Opt-Out**

The Services use cookies and similar technologies such as pixel tags, web beacons, clear GIFs and JavaScript (collectively, "Cookies") to enable our servers to recognize your web browser, tell us how and when you visit and use our Services, analyze trends, learn about our user base and operate and improve our Services. Cookies are small pieces of data– usually text files – placed on your computer, tablet, phone or similar device when you use that device to access our Services. We may also supplement the information we collect from you with information received from third parties, including third parties that have placed their own Cookies on your device(s). Please note that because of our use of Cookies, the Services do not support "Do Not Track" requests sent from a browser at this time.

We use the following types of Cookies:

* Essential Cookies. Essential Cookies are required for providing you with features or services that you have requested. For example, certain Cookies enable you to log into secure areas of our Services. Disabling these Cookies may make certain features and services unavailable.
* Functional Cookies. Functional Cookies are used to record your choices and settings regarding our Services, maintain your preferences over time and recognize you when you return to our Services. These Cookies help us to personalize our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).
* Performance/Analytical Cookies. Performance/Analytical Cookies allow us to understand how visitors use our Services. They do this by collecting information about the number of visitors to the Services, what pages visitors view on our Services and how long visitors are viewing pages on the Services. Performance/Analytical Cookies also help us measure the performance of our advertising campaigns in order to help us improve our campaigns and the Services' content for those who engage with our advertising. For example, Google Inc. ("Google") uses cookies in connection with its Google Analytics services. Google's ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the Services is subject to the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You have the option to opt-out of Google's use of Cookies by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page at www.google.com/privacy\_ads.html or the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on at [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).
* Retargeting/Advertising Cookies. Retargeting/Advertising Cookies collect data about your online activity and identify your interests. We may utilize retargeting/advertising cookies to advertise our Services to you on third party websites. We will not show you third party advertisements on our website(s).

You can decide whether or not to accept Cookies through your internet browser's settings. Most browsers have an option for turning off the Cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new Cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allow you to decide on acceptance of each new Cookie in a variety of ways. You can also delete all Cookies that are already on your device. If you do this, however, you may have to manually adjust some preferences every time you visit our website and some of the Services and functionalities may not work.

To explore what Cookie settings are available to you or to modify your preferences with respect to Cookies, you can access your Cookie management settings by clicking the "Cookie Preferences" link at the bottom of our website. To find out more information about Cookies, including information about how to manage and delete Cookies, please visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org/](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**Information about Interest-Based Advertisements**

We may work with third-party ad networks, including third-party ad servers, ad agencies, ad technology vendors and research firms, to serve advertisements to you. These advertisements may be targeted to users who fit certain general profile categories or display certain preferences or behaviors ("Interest-Based Ads"). Information for Interest-Based Ads (including Personal Data) may be provided to us by you, or derived from the usage patterns of particular users on the Services and/or services of third parties. Such information may be gathered through tracking users' activities across time and unaffiliated properties, including when you leave the Services. To accomplish this, we or our service providers may deliver Cookies, including a file (known as a "web beacon") from an ad network to you through the Services. Web beacons allow ad networks to provide anonymized, aggregated auditing, research and reporting for us and for advertisers. Web beacons also enable ad networks to serve targeted advertisements to you when you visit other websites. Web beacons allow ad networks to view, edit or set their own Cookies on your browser, just as if you had requested a web page from their site.

**Data Security and Retention**

We seek to protect your Personal Data from unauthorized access, use and disclosure using appropriate physical, technical, organizational and administrative security measures based on the type of Personal Data and how we are processing that data. You should also help protect your data by appropriately selecting and protecting your password and/or other sign-on mechanism; limiting access to your computer or device and browser; and signing off after you have finished accessing your account. Although we work to protect the security of your account and other data that we hold in our records, please be aware that no method of transmitting data over the internet or storing data is completely secure.

**Data Retention**

We retain Personal Data about you for as long as necessary to provide you with our Services or to perform our business or commercial purposes for collecting your Personal Data. When establishing a retention period for specific categories of data, we consider who we collected the data from, our need for the Personal Data, why we collected the Personal Data, and the sensitivity of the Personal Data. In some cases we retain Personal Data for longer, if doing so is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes or collect fees owed, or is otherwise permitted or required by applicable law, rule or regulation. We may further retain information in an anonymous or aggregated form where that information would not identify you personally.

For example, we retain your profile information and credentials for as long as you have an account with us.

**Personal Data of Children**

As noted in the Terms of Use, we do not knowingly collect or solicit Personal Data about children under 18 years of age; if you are a child under the age of 18, please do not attempt to register for or otherwise use the Services or send us any Personal Data. If we learn we have collected Personal Data from a child under 18 years of age, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 18 years of age may have provided Personal Data to us, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.monarchmoney.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**California Resident Rights**

If you are a California resident, you have the rights set forth in this section. Please see the [Exercising Your Rights under the CCPA](#exercising-your-rights) section below for instructions regarding how to exercise these rights. Please note that we may process Personal Data of our customers' end users or employees in connection with our provision of certain services to our customers. If we are processing your Personal Data as a service provider, you should contact the entity that collected your Personal Data in the first instance to address your rights with respect to such data. Additionally, please note that these rights are subject to certain conditions and exceptions under applicable law, which may permit or require us to deny your request.

If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this Privacy Policy and you are a California resident, the portion that is more protective of Personal Data shall control to the extent of such conflict. If you have any questions about this section or whether any of the following rights apply to you, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.monarchmoney.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

_Access_

You have the right to request certain information about our collection and use of your Personal Data over the past 12 months. In response, we will provide you with the following information:

* The categories of Personal Data that we have collected about you.
* The categories of sources from which that Personal Data was collected.
* The business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling your Personal Data.
* The categories of third parties with whom we have shared your Personal Data.
* The specific pieces of Personal Data that we have collected about you.

If we have disclosed your Personal Data to any third parties for a business purpose over the past 12 months, we will identify the categories of Personal Data shared with each category of third party recipient. If we have sold your Personal Data over the past 12 months, we will identify the categories of Personal Data sold to each category of third party recipient.

You may request the above information beyond the 12-month period, but no earlier than January 1, 2022. If you do make such a request, we are required to provide that information unless doing so proves impossible or would involve disproportionate effort.

_Deletion_

You have the right to request that we delete the Personal Data that we have collected about you. Under the CCPA, this right is subject to certain exceptions: for example, we may need to retain your Personal Data to provide you with the Services or complete a transaction or other action you have requested. If your deletion request is subject to one of these exceptions, we may deny your deletion request.

_Correction_

You have the right to request that we correct any inaccurate Personal Data we have collected about you. Under the CCPA, this right is subject to certain exceptions: for example, if we decide, based on the totality of circumstances related to your Personal Data, that such data is correct. If your correction request is subject to one of these exceptions, we may deny your request.

_Personal Data Sales and Sharing Opt-Out_

In this section, we use the term "sell" and "share" as it is defined in the CCPA, which can include certain use of your Personal Data for online advertising. For clarity, we will only 'sell' or 'share' your Personal Data by way of Cookies, and not for monetary consideration. We do not sell your financial information.

As described in the "Tracking Tools, Advertising and Opt-Out" section above, we have incorporated Cookies from certain third parties into our Services. These Cookies allow those third parties to receive information about your activity on our Services that is associated with your browser or device. Those third parties may use that data to serve you relevant ads on our Services or on other websites you visit. Under the CCPA, disclosing your data through third party Cookies for online advertising may be considered "selling" or "sharing" of information. You can opt out by following the instructions in this section.

We sell or share your Personal Data to the following categories of third parties:

* Advertising Partners

Over the past 12 months, we may have sold or shared the following categories of your Personal Data to categories of third parties listed above:

* Device/IP Data
* Web Analytics

We may have sold or shared the foregoing categories of Personal Data for the following business or commercial purposes:

* Marketing the Services.
* Showing you advertisements, including interest-based or online behavioral advertising.

You have the right to opt-out of the sale or share of your Personal Data by following the instructions in the [Exercising Your Rights under the CCPA](#exercising-your-rights) section. Once you have submitted an opt-out request, we will not ask you to reauthorize the sale of your Personal Data for at least 12 months. To our knowledge, we do not sell or share the Personal Data of minors under 16 years of age.

_Limit the Use of Sensitive Personal Information_

Consumers have the right to request that we limit the use or sharing disclosure of their Sensitive Personal Information ("Right to Limit"). However, since our use and disclosure of Sensitive Information are limited to the purposes set forth in section 7027(m) of the CCPA regulations, including: 1) performing the services or providing the goods reasonably expected, 2) preventing, detecting, and investigating security incidents, 3) resisting malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal actions, 4) performing services on behalf of the business, 5) verifying or maintaining quality or safety of a product or service, and 6) collecting or processing Sensitive Personal Information but not for the purpose of inferring characteristics, we do not offer a way for you to submit such a request.

_We Will Not Discriminate Against You for Exercising Your Rights Under the CCPA_

We will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the CCPA. We will not deny you our goods or services, charge you different prices or rates, or provide you a lower quality of goods and services if you exercise your rights under the CCPA. However, we may offer different tiers of our Services as allowed by applicable data privacy laws (including the CCPA) with varying prices, rates or levels of quality of the goods or services you receive related to the value of Personal Data that we receive from you.

_Exercising Your Rights under the CCPA_

To exercise the rights described above, you or your designated authorized agent must send us a request that (1) provides sufficient information to allow us to verify that you are the person about whom we have collected Personal Data, and (2) describes your request in sufficient detail to allow us to understand, evaluate and respond to it. Each request that meets both of these criteria will be considered a "Valid Request." We may not respond to requests that do not meet these criteria.

You may opt-out from any "sales," or "shares," by using the following methods:

* By accessing your cookie consent mechanism by accessing your "Cookie Preferences" at the bottom left of our website.
* By implementing the Global Privacy Control or similar universal privacy control that is legally recognized by a government agency or industry standard and that complies with the CCPA. The signal issued by the control must be initiated by your browser and applies to the specific device and browser you use at the time you cast the signal. Please note this does not include Do Not Track signals.

You may submit a Valid Request for any other rights afforded to you under the CCPA using the following methods:

* You can delete your account within your account settings (See [https://help.monarchmoney.com/hc/en-us/articles/4412388754708-Delete-a-Monarch-Account](https://help.monarchmoney.com/hc/en-us/articles/4412388754708-Delete-a-Monarch-Account) for more information).
* Email us at: [\[email protected\]](https://www.monarchmoney.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
* Submit a form at this address: [https://help.monarchmoney.com/hc/en-us/requests/new](https://help.monarchmoney.com/hc/en-us/requests/new)

**Other State Law Privacy Rights**

_California Resident Rights_

Under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to contact us to prevent disclosure of Personal Data to third parties for such third parties' direct marketing purposes; in order to submit such a request, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.monarchmoney.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

If you are a resident of Nevada, you have the right to opt-out of the sale of certain Personal Data to third parties who intend to license or sell that Personal Data. You can exercise this right by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.monarchmoney.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) with the subject line "Nevada Do Not Sell Request" and providing us with your name and the email address associated with your account.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We're constantly trying to improve our Services, so we may need to change this Privacy Policy from time to time, but we will alert you of material changes by placing a notice on the Monarch website, by sending you an email and/or by some other means. Please note that if you've opted not to receive legal notice emails from us (or you haven't provided us with your email address), those legal notices will still govern your use of the Services, and you are still responsible for reading and understanding them. If you use the Services after any changes to the Privacy Policy have been posted, that means you agree to all of the changes. Use of information we collect is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected.

**Contact Information**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, the ways in which we collect and use your Personal Data or your choices and rights regarding such collection and use, please do not hesitate to contact us at:

* Website: [https://www.monarchmoney.com/](https://www.monarchmoney.com/)
* Phone: (206) 537-0692
* E-mail: [\[email protected\]](https://www.monarchmoney.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
* Address: 440 N Barranca Ave #3955, Covina, CA 91723
